TOMMY REDDAD

Montréal, Québec, Canada · ♥

reddad.ca · ❖
tommy.reddad@gmail.com · ☑
github.com/tommyreddad · •

linkedin.com/in/tommy-reddad · in

Profile

Programmer and computer scientist with 5 years of experience in academic research, specializing in applied probability theory, statistics, machine learning, and the analysis of algorithms. Fluent in Python.

Key Competences

Coding Utilities

Python, numpy, JavaScript, C(++), R, Emacs, git, LATEX, Visual Studio 2013 SQL, D3.js, React.js, OpenGL, HTML

Research and Leadership

Experienced in conducting advanced academic research in computer science and mathematics, both independently and through managing group projects. Strong communication and team skills. Ability to communicate and coordinate effectively with mathematicians and programmers alike.

Education

PhD student, Computer Science	2016-2019
McGill University, Montréal, Québec	GPA: 4.00/4.00
Master of Computer Science	2013-2015
Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario	GPA: 11.8/12.0
Master's thesis: Encoding Arguments	
BSc, Joint Honours in Mathematics and Computer Science	2010—2013
McGill University	GPA: $3.92/4.00$

Professional Experience

Doctoral Researcher

McGill University 2016—2019

- Studied various problems in minimax density estimation (1 peer-reviewed journal article, 2 other papers), and the detection of the spread of an infection in a random network (1 peer-reviewed journal article.)
- Awarded the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada's Postgraduate Doctoral Scholarship through 2017—2019.

Teaching Assistant

McGill University 2016—2019 Carleton University 2013—2015

Held weekly office hours for diverse undergraduate and graduate level university courses in computer science, with responsibilities including grading, designing homework questions, and lecturing.

Research Assistant

Carleton University 2013—2015 McGill University 2012, 2013

• Studied encoding arguments as a proof technique (1 peer-reviewed journal article, Master's thesis), the Shannon capacity of graphs, and the geometric analysis of maps and balance in competitive multiplayer video games (1 paper).